Guide to the Blukis Onat Applied Sciences (BOAS), Inc. Papers 1968-2010
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- SR 520 Corridor, Bridge Replacement, Proposed Pontoon Construction Site at Port of Grays Harbor Industrial Development District (IDD) Parcel No. 1, Hoquiam, including 45GH130, IDD Cultural Resource Study for the Washington State Department of Transportation (WSDOT), Grays Harbor County: artifact catalog sheets; field notes specific to crew member; photograph logs; photocopies of historic aerial photographs and maps of Grays Harbor and Hoquiam (1841, 1884, 1928, 1952, 1972, 1973, 1981, 1985, 1997); photocopies of historic documents such as Grays Harbor County Index to Fishing Location Maps (1915-1934, 1939); project maps; and stratigraphic core logs., undated, 1841, 1884, 1915-34, 1939, 1952, 1972, 1973, 1981, 1985, 1997, 2006, 2007 (Box-folder 50/3-9, Project 200511.03)
- SR 520 Corridor, Bridge Replacement, Proposed Pontoon Construction Site at Port of Grays Harbor Industrial Development District (IDD) Parcel No. 1 in Hoquiam, IDD Cultural Resource Preliminary Discipline Report for the Washington State Department of Transportation, Grays Harbor County: 13 data CDs (200511.03) with field notes, photos, maps, and report; and 8x10 inch black-and-white copies of 1940 and 1948 photographs of Hoquiam., 1940, 1948, 2007 (Box-folder 79/23, Project 200511.03)
- SR 520 Corridor, Bridge Replacement: specialized analyses and reports, radiocarbon and botanical; WSDOT Special Projects Construction communiques and documents, miscellaneous; miscellaneous items., undated, 2006, 2007 (Box-folder 51/1-3, Project 200511.03)
- Strander Pump Station Construction Excavations in City of Tukwila, Archaeological Monitoring, King County: 3 data CDs with report and photos; field notes; and letter report., 2005 (Box-folder 51/4-5, Project 200512, 200512a)
- Sites 45SK308, 309, 310, and 311 and Sauk-Suiattle Indian Tribe Archaeology Project on Land under WA State Department of Natural Resources and Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest as well as private timberlands, Cultural Resources Identification based on Tribal Elder Knowledge of Traditional Properties especially on Sauk Prairie and along Sauk and Suiattle Rivers and including Glacier Peak with Native Plant Identification, funded by National Park Service, Snohomish and Skagit Counties: 5 data CDs, 4 images only and 1 site form documents and images; correspondence; contracts and subconsultant agreements; native plant lists; photographic logs and photocopies of photo contact sheets; and site forms., 2004-2006 (Box-folder 51/6, Project 200513)
- Lummi Reservation, Site 45WH171 and Casino to Membrane Bioreactor Plant (MBR) Sewer Force Main Project, LUP 2004-091, Archaeological Assessment Summary for Lummi Indian Business Council, Whatcom County: letter report., 2005 (Box-folder 51/7, Project 200514)
- 45KI1451 (Seattle Lake Shore & Eastern Railroad Grade), 45 KI648 (North Bend Ranger Station), and 45KI658 (McGrath Café and Hotel) and City of North Bend’s North Bend Way/Cedar Falls Way Intersection Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Investigations, King County: 1 data CD with photos, associated images, and documents; background documents; field notes; site forms; and letter report., 2005-2006 (Box-folder 51/8, Project 200515)
- Burke Gilman Trail Redevelopment, Cultural Resources Investigations, King County: correspondence and report., 2007 (Box-folder 51/9, Project 200516)
- 45WH112 and Private Property Improvement Project on Lummi Reservation, Review of Cultural Resources and Archaeological Survey, Whatcom County: letter report., 2005 (Box-folder 51/10, Project 200517)
- Site DT26 (Everett and Monte Cristo Railroad) and Proposed Granite Falls Alternate Route, Historic-Era Properties Documentation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: report., 2007 (Box-folder 51/11, Project 200601.01)
- Sauk River Bridge #414 Replacement, Cultural Resource Inventory for Department of Public Works and Historic American Engineering Record for bridge prepared by SHKS Architects, Snohomish County: 1 data CD with HAER documentation and report., 2005-2006 (Box-folder 51/12, Project 200601.02, 200601.02a (HAER))
- May Creek Bridge No. 572 Replacement, Cultural Resource Inventory for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: report., 2006 (Box-folder 52/1, Project 200601.03)
- 51st Avenue NE Intersection Improvements, Cultural Resources Evaluation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: letter report., 2006 (Box-folder 52/2, Project 200601.04)
- Proposed Erosion Control with Wood Replacement on the Skykomish River, Cultural Resources Investigations for Surface Water Management Division, Snohomish County: correspondence; field notes; and report., 2005-2006 (Box-folder 52/3, Project 200601.05)
- Marten Creek Bridge No. 562 Replacement, Cultural Resource Inventory for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: reports., 2006-2007 (Box-folder 52/4, Project 200601.08 (see also 200306.18))
- Lowell-Snohomish River Trail, Cultural Resources Investigations for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: report., 2006 (Box-folder 52/5, Project 200601.09)
- Jim Creek Bridge #42 Replacement Project, Archaeological Survey and Testing Results and Historic Property Inventory for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: data CD, correspondence, and reports., 2007-2008 (Box-folder 52/6-7, Project 200601.10, 200601.10a)
- Sauk River Mouse Creek Bridge #631 Replacement, Cultural Resource Inventory for Department of Public Works with Mt. Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest as lead agency in tribal consultations, Snohomish County: field notes; project maps; and report., 2006 (Box-folder 52/8, Project 200601.11)
- Improvement Projects in Unincorporated Areas, Cultural Resources Investigations for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: data CD; field notes; letter report and report., 2006-2007 (Box-folder 52/9-10, Project 200601.12, 200601.13)
- 20th Street SE Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Inventory for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: report., 2006-2007 (Box-folder 52/11, Project 200601.14a)
- 20th Street SE Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Inventory for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: 5 data CDs with project spreadsheets, documents for reports, and photos; field notes; project maps and aerial photos; and reports., 2006-2007 (Box-folder 53/1-2, Project 200601.14a, 200601.14b)
- South Slough Bridge #91 Deck Replacement, Cultural Resource Inventory for County Department of Public Works and Intensive Level Survey of Bridge Structure by SHKS Architects for Washington State Department of Archaeology & Historic Preservation, Snohomish County: 2 data CDs with field notes, photos and report; American Public Works Association Award for South Slough Bridge #91 as National Project of the 2008 Year in the under $2 million Transportation Category; and reports., 2007-2008 (Box-folder 53/3-4, Project 200601.15a, 200601.15b)
- North Sauk River and Engebretsen Road Improvement Projects and 45SN427 and 45SN428, Historic Sites on Gold Mountain, Cultural Resource Investigations including Consultations with Sauk-Suiattle and Stillaguamish Tribes for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: correspondence; field notes; project maps and aerial photographs; supporting documents; letter and bound reports., 2006-2007 (Box-folder 53/5-6, Project 200601.17, 200601.18)
- Assorted Public Works Improvement Projects, Cultural Resources Studies for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: data CDs with background documents, photographs, photo log, project maps and aerial photos, report figures, and shovel probe tables; field notes; letter reports., 2007 (Box-folder 54/1, 4-5, Project 200601.19, 200601.22, 200601.23)
- Historic American Engineering Record (HAER) for Granite Falls Bridge #102 and Department of Archaeology and Historic Preservation Reconnaissance Level Survey for 29 Homes on Beverly Park Road/52nd Avenue West Road Improvement Project and Historic Structure Survey State Inventory Form for Fleet Maintenance Building, Paine Field, SHKS Architects subcontracted by BOAS for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: 2 data CDs for Fleet Maintenance Building include documents, photographs, report file; and bound reports., 2007-2008 (Box-folder 54/2-3, 6, Project 200601.20, 200601.21, 200601.28)
- Snohomish County Lushootseed Place Name Maps for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: bound report., 2009 (Box-folder 70R/1, Project 200601.27)
- Keystone Harbor, Whidbey Island, Archaeological Monitoring of Geotechnical Boring for Washington State Department of Transportation, Island County: 1 data CD with field notes; field notes; and summary report., 2006 (Box-folder 54/7, Project 200603)
- Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45SN301, Archaeological Survey, Snohomish County: letter report., 2006 (Box-folder 54/8, Project 200605)
- Vashon Island Seawall Repair in Multiple Locations and Sites 45KI550, KING 1035, KING 7403 (Indian Point), and WPA Seawall on SW Quartermaster Drive, Cultural Resources Section 106 Compliance for King County Road Services Division: E.O. Roberts photocopies of notes on collections from 1919-1922 for Quartermaster Harbor from Burke Museum (Accession 2411, 1930, 1996); background documents; field notes; project maps; and technical report., 1930, 1996, 2003, 2006 (Box-folder 54/9, Project 200606.01)
- South Park Bridge Project, Demolition and Replacement of National Register of Historic Places (NRHP)-Listed South Park Bridge, Section 106 Assessment of Sites Lwalb Old Channel One and Lwalb Old Channel Two, NRHP-Eligible Boeing Building 2-41 and 14th Avenue South Red Brick Road remnant, and Lushootseed Place Name Ethnography for King County Road Services Division: technical report., June 2008 (Box-folder 54/10, Project 200606.02)
- South Park Bridge Project, Demolition and Replacement of National Register of Historic Places (NRHP)-Listed South Park Bridge, Section 106 Assessment of Sites Lwalb Old Channel One and Lwalb Old Channel Two, NRHP-Eligible Boeing Building 2-41 and 14th Avenue South Red Brick Road remnant, and Lushootseed Place Name Ethnography for King County Road Services Division: data CD with photographs, photo log, correspondence; field notes; and project maps., 2007-2008 (Box-folder 55/1, Project 200606.02)
- NE Novelty Hill Road Project, Multi-phase Mitigation for Precontact (Olcott Complex?) Site 45KI834, Assessment of Historic Properties including Section of NRHP-listed Red Brick/Yellowstone Road, and Other Section 106 Compliance for King County Road Services Division: 5 technical reports., 2007-2010 (Box-folder 55/2-4, Project 200606.03)
- Duwamish River Bend Hill Trail (aka Poverty Hill) Development in City of Tukwila, Cultural Resource Assessment Survey for Cascade Land Conservancy, King County: data CD with field notes, maps, photographs, and report; aerial photographs; trail master plan; and report., 2007 (Box-folder 55/5, Project 200607)
- North Creek Trail Crossing in City of Mill Creek, Cultural Resources Investigations, Snohomish County: report., 2007 (Box-folder 56/1, Project 200609)
- 45SN303 (NRHP-eligible Olcott Complex site) and River Walk Subdivision near Granite Falls, Archaeological Investigations, Snohomish County: archaeological excavation permit application; correspondence; documentation of records and cultural materials transmittal to Burke Museum (2010); and report., 2006-2007, 2010 (Box-folder 56/2, Project 200610)
- Site 45SN301 and Classroom Additions to Dutch Hill Elementary School in the City of Snohomish, Archaeological Survey, Snohomish County: data CD with report and other documents; field notes; and letter report., 2006 (Box-folder 56/3, Project 200611)
- Lopez Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45SJ272, Cultural Resource Study, San Juan County: photo CD; correspondence; field notes; and report., 2006-2007 (Box-folder 56/4, Project 200614)
- First Avenue NE Transfer/Recycling Station in the City of Seattle, On-call Osteological Assessment for Solid Waste Division, King County: letter identifying bones as likely bovine., October 2006 (Box-folder 56/5, Project 200615)
- Darrington Town Hall and Library Expansion Project in the Town of Darrington, Cultural Resource Study, Snohomish County: letter report., November 2007 (Box-folder 56/6, Project 200701)
- Duwamish River Bend Hill Trail (aka Poverty Hill) Development in City of Tukwila, Shovel Probe Subsurface Testing in Cultural Resource Assessment for Cascade Land Conservancy, King County: 2 data CDs with field notes, maps, photographs, and report; field note; maps; and reports., 2007-2008 (Box-folder 56/7, Project 200703 (see 200607))
- Penny Creek Culvert Project in the City of Mill Creek, Cultural Resource Study, Snohomish County: data CD with correspondence, photographs, and project plans; and letter report., 2007 (Box-folder 56/8, Project 200704)
- Public Works Projects in the Town of Darrington, Potential for Archaeological Resources Assessment, Snohomish County: report., 2011 (Box-folder 56/9, Project 201004)
- Processing and Collection Documentation file: includes donor's original transmittal list; and "BOAS History," narrative history of BOAS, Inc., and professional autobiography of Astrika Blukis Onat. (Box-folder 56/10)
- Processing file: reference materials supplied by Astrida Blukis Onat. (Box-folder 56/11)
- Processing file: Documentation of Contacts for Permission to Access and Copy Restricted items (Box-folder 56/12)
- Use Agreement Forms. (Box-folder 56/13)